var QuestionDatabase =

[
// Chapter 1
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false],"question":"SELECT is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false],"question":"INSERT is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false],"question":"UPDATE is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false],"question":"DELETE is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false],"question":"MERGE is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false],"question":"CREATE is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false],"question":"ALTER is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false],"question":"DROP is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false],"question":"RENAME is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false],"question":"TRUNCATE is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false],"question":"GRANT is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false],"question":"REVOKE is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false],"question":"FLASHBACK is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false],"question":"PURGE is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false],"question":"COMMENT is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true],"question":"COMMIT is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["DML","DDL","TCL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true],"question":"ROLLBACK is a _____ type of SQL command."},
{"answers":["SELECT","UPDATE","ALTER","CREATE","GRANT"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to instantiate a new database object, such as a user, table, view, index, or synonym?","category":0},
{"answers":["SELECT","UPDATE","ALTER","CREATE","GRANT"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to modify an existing database object's structure or attributes?","category":0},
{"answers":["DELETE","DROP","ALTER","PURGE","REVOKE","ROLLBACK"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to remove an object from the database?","category":0},
{"answers":["SELECT","UPDATE","ALTER","CREATE","GRANT"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to instantiate a new database object, such as a user, table, view, index, or synonym?","category":0},
{"answers":["SELECT","UPDATE","ALTER","CREATE","GRANT"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to modify an existing database object's structure or attributes?","category":0},
{"answers":["DELETE","DROP","PURGE","ALTER","ROLLBACK"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to remove an object from the database?","category":0},
{"answers":["ALTER","UPDATE","RENAME","COMMENT","CREATE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to alter the name of an existing database object?","category":0},
{"answers":["TRUNCATE","DELETE","ROLLBACK","DROP","PURGE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to immediately remove all records from a table, partition or subpartition?","category":0},
{"answers":["REVOKE","ALTER","CREATE","SELECT","GRANT"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Which SQL command is used to provide privileges, or rights, to user objects?","category":0},
{"answers":["DELETE","TRUNCATE","REVOKE","DROP","REMOVE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to remove privileges that have been issued to a user object?","category":0},
{"answers":["RESTORE","FLASHBACK","ROLLBACK","UPDATE","REVERT"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to restore a table or database to a previous version?","category":0},
{"answers":["TRUNCATE","EMPTY","PURGE","DROP","COMMIT"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to irreversibly remove an object from the recycle bin?","category":0},
{"answers":["ALTER","COMMENT","UPDATE","REFERENCE","ANNOTATE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to add a comment to the data dictionary for a database object?","category":0},
{"answers":["INSERT","DATA","SELECT","SHOW","DISPLAY"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to display data in a table or view?","category":0},
{"answers":["CREATE","INSERT","ALERT","UPDATE","ROW"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command is used to add new rows to a table?","category":0},
{"answers":["UPDATE","ALTER","MODIFY","INSERT","RENAME"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command modifies existing rows in a table?","category":0},
{"answers":["TRUNCATE","DROP","DELETE","REMOVE","PURGE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command iteratively removes a subset of existing rows from a table, as optionally defined by a WHERE clause?","category":0},
{"answers":["UPDATE","INSERT","ALTER","MERGE","DELETE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,true,false],"question":"Which SQL command selects rows from one or more sources for update, insertion, or exclusion into a table?","category":0},
{"answers":["SAVE","SAVEPOINT","COMMIT","ROLLBACK","EXECUTE IMMEDIATE"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command saves the set of DML statements executed in the current database session?","category":0},
{"answers":["DELETE","FLASHBACK","REVOKE","RESET","ROLLBACK"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,false,false,true],"question":"Which SQL command revokes the set of DML statements executed in the current databse session?","category":0},
{"answers":["FLASHBACK","SAVEPOINT","COMMIT","TRANSACTION","ROLLBACK"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,false,false,false],"question":"Which SQL command marks a position in the current session to which a future ROLLBACK will revert?","category":0},
{"answers":["Schema","Non-Schema"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false],"question":"A CONSTRAINT is a _______ object.","category":9},
{"answers":["Schema","Non-Schema"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false],"question":"A SEQUENCE is a _______ object.","category":9},
{"answers":["Schema","Non-Schema"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false],"question":"An INDEX is a _______ object.","category":9},
{"answers":["Schema","Non-Schema"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false],"question":"A PRIVATE SYNONYM is a _______ object.","category":9},
{"answers":["Schema","Non-Schema"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false],"question":"A TABLE is a _______ object.","category":9},
{"answers":["Schema","Non-Schema"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false],"question":"A VIEW is a _______ object.","category":9},
{"answers":["Schema","Non-Schema"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true],"question":"A ROLE is a _______ object.","category":9},
{"answers":["Schema","Non-Schema"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true],"question":"A PUBLIC SYNONYM is a _______ object.","category":9},
{"answers":["Schema","Non-Schema"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true],"question":"A USER is a _______ object.","category":9},

// Chapter 2
{"answers":["Schema","Nonschema"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false],"question":"______ objects are those that can be owned by a user.","category":10},
{"answers":["Schema","Nonschema"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true],"question":"_______ objects are those that cannot be owned by a user.","category":10},
{"answers":["A USER object can own itself","A USER object can be owned by another USER object","A USER object is a nonschema object","A USER object can own a PRIVATE SYNONYM"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,false,true,true],"question":"Which of the following are true about USER objects?","category":10},
{"answers":["PUBLIC","DUAL","SYSTEM","SYS","INTERNAL"],"correctAnswerIndexes":[true,false,false,false,false],"question":"A PUBLIC SYNONYM is owned by the special user account _______.","category":10},
{"answers":["Object names are case sensitive","All database objects MUST have a name.","Names can contain letters, '$', '_' or '#'.","Object names MUST start with a letter.","Object names can contain spaces."],"correctAnswerIndexes":[false,true,true,true,false],"question":"Which of the following are true of UNQUOTED database object names?","category":10}

]; 